<DOC DOCNO="tc/ch/00/ch_0006@0006@ch@tc@en@on">
%huh ?
What price ?
%uh , free Free ! which is even better , yes
Wow .
mhm .
But what about you ?
%uh , then I 'll work on me .
%uh because see if I do n't I , if I do n't get back %uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</ENAMEX> it 's no big deal .
I could just stay here .
So it 's not important for me .
Right .
You see ?
So the main thing is to get your , your deal .
So you might not come back here ?
Right .
Got you .
Right .
So you do n't need
Because I do n't have to do anything but work <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</ENAMEX>
so .
Right .
Well what happens to your work then ?
Well I just wo n't do it .
But I mean if I have to pay you know , <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">a thousand dollars</ENAMEX> it 's not expeditious to make <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</ENAMEX> and That 's a big word . Those crosswords are making you use big words . pay <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</ENAMEX> .
Is that what it is ?
Getting better ?
uh-huh .
mhm %hm
That 's the purpose .
uh-huh .
Increase your word power .
mhm .
So %um Well you know that would , that would be the the thing .
I mean there 's no way
I 'm sure you 're not going to get back %uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">within a day or two</ENAMEX> of the time . You know because there 're <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighteen hundred</ENAMEX> flights that %uh that go back .
I 'm not on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">American</ENAMEX> .
On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">American</ENAMEX> .
On <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">American</ENAMEX> .
They go from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> .
oh this is a flight to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> ?
Right .
I see .
Right .
Can you get me a connecting flight ?
Well that should n't be a problem .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX> said there 's no inter-Europe flights .
Right .
Right .
No ,
I can go down to the place here and
Sure .
Sure .
No ,
everybody who does n't have a ticket <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">a month ago</ENAMEX> is not going to fly for <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the rest of the year</ENAMEX> .
okay
You see ?
mhm .
%um
I 'm eating a banana ,
excuse me .
It just
I see .
that 's the
Well
You know to have a sh-
you know
And I 'd have to stand by in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> by myself .
uh-huh .
Like a big girl ,
yes .
Yes .
Exactly .
but exactly .
That 's the , that 's the thing .
You know we just pick a , Amazing . just pick a day %uh you know
Right .
%um <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Mondays</ENAMEX> sometimes people coming back
but %uh , you know nobody leaves on <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesdays</ENAMEX> .
Well do you think it would be better to come like on <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">that Friday the twenty - first</ENAMEX>
%uh , well I mean that 's some- Can we do that ? %mm that 's something you could do .
%uh , you know the other thing is
Because if you 're not coming anyways then Right . I do n't have to fly with you so I could just come <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">that Friday</ENAMEX> .
Right .
Well , the other thing is is that you could just stay longer .
Right .
Exactly .
Get a short flight .
Just stay longer .
Well , yeah ,
but
mhm .
Maybe you came like <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the twenty first</ENAMEX> %uh ,
that way then .
uh-huh .
If you can change it .
Well I can probably change it .
duh , duh , buh , buh , duh duh .
They %uh , they there ?
What ?
What day are they t- , here ?
Hold on .
You do n't have the paper .
oh .
Well I no I got it .
I g-
so yeah you 'd get here <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the twenty second</ENAMEX> .
It is true .
%um
You know
uh-huh .
Right .
Right .
okay .
%um , Where was that paper by the way ?
Which paper ?
The paper that
I copied it for you and gave it to you .
No . No .
I mean where was it when you told me I had it and I told you you had it .
Who had it ?
I do n't know .
I do n't know .
Where did it come from ?
It 's history .
It 's history detective .
Who , where did it come from ? 458.93_461.27_A:
The important thing is that we have it .
I want to be able to say I told you so .
No . No . No .
I I No , I know that .
I know that .
I know that well .
That 's the most important thing in your life .
Yes .
No .
I know that very well .
Yes .
You 're just not happy to have it .
You have to get some , got to get some justice .
I told you dumb shit .
No .
I , I know the program .
It 's tough .
It 's tough .
%uh , so what I 'll do then is %uh then I 'll go ahead and get it then .
okay .
%um
Will you have any money I can stand by ?
I 've got
Like go get a hotel if I have to ?
oh I 'll have some money by then .
oh right .
%uh , no .
Right .
Everybody will have the stuff by then .
yeah .
That wo n't be a problem .
mhm .
Wo n't be a problem .
But I 'll %uh see if we can get a <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</ENAMEX> way and then buy another <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</ENAMEX> way going back .
Where 's this ticket , this ticket is to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> ?
%uh no get it to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nice</ENAMEX> , from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nice</ENAMEX> .
Right .
Right .
No .
I mean coming ,
when I leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L A</ENAMEX> the where do I fly to ?
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> ?
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> .
mhm yeah .
And then I 'll have to take a boat because there 's no , no inter-Europe's according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX> .
%ah Right .
yep .
No .
It 's , it 's great .
Well let me know .
%uh no .
I 'll go ahead and %uh do it .
okay
And %uh I 'll go and talk to the person here cause they get cheap tickets %uh okay . from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nice</ENAMEX> and stuff .
Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil</ENAMEX> still there ?
%uh yep .
yep .
yep .
Exactly .
He 's never going home .
%uh let 's see
We 'll go there again when %uh you come .
okay .
It 's really good restaurant .
They were people who went to the jazz festival with me <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</ENAMEX> .
They own the restaurant .
oh sure .
So they 'll probably want to go with us <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</ENAMEX> .
That 's fine .
Nice people .
Cool .
Cool .
Cool .
Cool
yes yes .
So have any of your things closed ?
No .
Nothing
Nothing .
Right .
That was a dream .
So he still has n't made any inroads ?
%uh %uh .
Nothing %huh ?
uh-huh .
It may not happen .
oh god .
If that does n't happen he 'll commit suicide .
The station ?
Right .
He 'll be in bad shape .
mhm
and then that 's because everybody involved will get sued .
What do you mean ?
Everybody involved ?
Does that mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirl Clay</ENAMEX> ?
Probably .
Why ?
I do n't think they can
but I think they 'll try .
You know how people are .
</DOC>
