<DOC DOCNO="bn/cnn/01/cnn_0188@0188@cnn@bn@en@on">
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> Ambassador to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX> is safe after a plane hijacking in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yemen</ENAMEX> .
A man claiming to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Iraqi</ENAMEX> supporter of President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> hijacked the flight with <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</ENAMEX> passengers on board , demanding to be flown to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> .
The pilot managed to land the plane in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Djibouti</ENAMEX> , where most of the passengers got off , including the ambassador .
</DOC>
