<DOC DOCNO="bn/cnn/01/cnn_0102@0102@cnn@bn@en@on">
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">United Nations</ENAMEX> special envoy is warning of a `` increasingly desperate '' situation for <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Palestinians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaza</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">the West Bank</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Israeli</ENAMEX> security restrictions on cross-border movement have cut humanitarian aid and fuel supplies to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Palestinian</ENAMEX> territories .
</DOC>
