<DOC DOCNO="bn/cnn/00/cnn_0025@0025@cnn@bn@en@on">
Our top story <ENAMEX TYPE="TIME">this half hour</ENAMEX> -- the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">United Nations</ENAMEX> Secretary - General says it 's a time of `` delicate and acute diplomacy '' in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOC">the Middle East</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX> says he 's ready to accept a commission to look into the causes of the recent clashes , an outside commission .
I think we should avoid any statements or anything , on both sides , that will lead to tension on either side .
Clashes in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">the West Bank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaza</ENAMEX> have left scores injured and <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 90</ENAMEX> people have been killed .
Once again , here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ramallah</ENAMEX> , confrontation , <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Palestinian</ENAMEX> demonstrators coming up against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Israeli</ENAMEX> security forces .
Throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="TIME">the afternoon</ENAMEX> , the security forces have been firing rubber - coated steel bullets , they 've been using concussion grenades and they 've been firing tear gas into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Palestinian</ENAMEX> crowd , which has been responding with stones and on occasion , fire bombs .
What happened on <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">this particular day</ENAMEX> , a funeral was held for a man who was allegedly beaten to death by <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Jewish</ENAMEX> settlers .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Palestinians</ENAMEX> attended this funeral here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ramallah</ENAMEX> and came down to this particular point where there was another confrontation with security forces , one that has occurred numerous times over <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 13 days</ENAMEX> .
Of those <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</ENAMEX> people had been wounded with sharp - point high velocity ammunition , that is regular bullets , not rubber - coated steel bullets , that is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 50 %</ENAMEX> of those admitted have been injured according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ramallah</ENAMEX> hospital authorities with regular bullets .
Earlier on , I spoke to the authorities , was provided with statistics that indicate over <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 13 days</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 40 %</ENAMEX> of those admitted had been treated for injuries skin with the high velocity regular bullets , a disturbing fact indeed .
One must point out as well , there has been relative quiet , relative to the high intensity of violence that has been seen , but here at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ramallah</ENAMEX> , the far northern border of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX> , once again there 's confrontation tags and conflict .
I 'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Hanna</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">CNN</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ramallah</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
