<DOC DOCNO="bn/cnn/00/cnn_0084@0084@cnn@bn@en@on">
C is manufactured in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">the United States</ENAMEX> and other countries such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> .
Sources say identification of the explosive will allow authorities to focus on terrorist groups that have access to it .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">CNN</ENAMEX> has obtained photographs which show the extent of the damage to the `` <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cole</ENAMEX> . ''
Repairs could run <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">as high as $ 170 million</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</ENAMEX> sailors died in the bombing .
</DOC>
