<DOC DOCNO="wb/p2.5_a2e/00/p2.5_a2e_0008@0008@p2.5_a2e@wb@en@on">
One day , after ten years of his stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> , coincidentally , one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Saudi</ENAMEX> princes came to the state where this young man resided , and this prince asked for a translator for the doctors .
They told him that there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Saudi</ENAMEX> young man in the same state who had mastered the <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">English</ENAMEX> language , so he told them to bring him to translate for me what the doctors say .
This young man came and spent a month with the prince , translating for him while he stayed in the hospital .
This young man thought to himself and said , I have been here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> for ten years , and I did not send one letter to my family .
I do not know anything about them .
This prince after only one month sent a poem of longing to his family .
When the company learned that this young man had decided to return to his homeland , unfortunately <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> fights every <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Arab</ENAMEX> talented mind , it made him a victim of heroin and alcohol until he went half crazy .
After that , they allowed him to return to his homeland .
</DOC>
