<DOC DOCNO="wb/p2.5_c2e/00/p2.5_c2e_0053@0053@p2.5_c2e@wb@en@on">
In just <ENAMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">nine</ENAMEX> short days , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">netizens</ENAMEX> have shown an unprecedented enthusiasm and concern for the proposal given by " <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Tian Nan Di Bei</ENAMEX> . "
Even though he has n't been selected as an academician of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Chinese Academy of Sciences</ENAMEX> , and has n't won <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">a Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> , none of this can disguise the holy brilliance that he personally possesses . "
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">netizens</ENAMEX> think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yuan Longping 's</ENAMEX> repeated winning of major international awards shows international approval and praise for the great contribution in research and promotion aspects of hybrid rice made by those , represented by him , working in rice breeding in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> over many years .
</DOC>
