<DOC DOCNO="wb/p2.5_c2e/00/p2.5_c2e_0036@0036@p2.5_c2e@wb@en@on">
Something else is also making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li Yan</ENAMEX> happy .
The elder sister of the international goalkeeper coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jia Chunhua</ENAMEX> is currently helping out as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li Yan 's</ENAMEX> " nanny , " successfully solving the problem of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li Yan 's</ENAMEX> meals .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jia Chunhua 's</ENAMEX> elder sister happens to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Auckland</ENAMEX> , the arena where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Knights</ENAMEX> are based .
" I only have to go downstairs and walk across a street to get to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jia Chunhua 's</ENAMEX> elder sister 's home , " <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li Yan</ENAMEX> said with a smile .
A few days ago when he had not yet found a place to live , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li Yan</ENAMEX> had been worried about his meals , but now the issue of meals has been smoothly resolved .
They are so kind to me that I even feel a bit uneasy ! "
</DOC>
