<DOC DOCNO="wb/p2.5_a2e/00/p2.5_a2e_0004@0004@p2.5_a2e@wb@en@on">
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Special Force for Road Safety</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOC">the Qusaim district</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="LOC">Um Sedra Center</ENAMEX> , was able to arrest a <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Saudi</ENAMEX> person and another person of <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Arab</ENAMEX> nationality , after the second had smuggled a very large quantity of prohibited amphetamine pills , numbering more than 397 thousand pills inside his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mercedes</ENAMEX> car at exactly three in the morning , thinking that the early hour would help him go past the road guards on his way to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOC">Riyadh</ENAMEX> .
The details of the case , after the arrest of the first person in whose possession were ten pills of the same kind that were seized , are that while there was no relation or connection between the two arrested men , the car was going back and forth between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOC">the Kingdom</ENAMEX> and his country , which made the road guards suspicious of a concealed matter .
Accordingly , the 1997 <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mercedes</ENAMEX> vehicle was searched .
Immediately after they were seized , the arrested men were handed over directly to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Drug Combating Department</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
