<DOC DOCNO="bn/voa/00/voa_0076@0076@voa@bn@en@on">
The meeting came after <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Israeli</ENAMEX> soldiers and <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Palestinians</ENAMEX> were killed on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">the West Bank</ENAMEX> .
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> , acting <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Israeli</ENAMEX> Foreign Minister <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shalome Ben - Ami</ENAMEX> called the situation extremely grave .
It is , let us call it a war or if you prefer , a mini war .
So , this is a war in many senses and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Palestinians</ENAMEX> are shooting at our soldiers , and therefore we need to address this issue not as a civilian uprising , but as a military confrontation .
<ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least 160</ENAMEX> people have been killed in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five weeks</ENAMEX> , most of them <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Palestinians</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
