<DOC DOCNO="bn/voa/00/voa_0018@0018@voa@bn@en@on">
President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> says he hopes his talks with the top <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">North Korean</ENAMEX> envoy here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</ENAMEX> will help promote reconciliation with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pyongyang</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
