<DOC DOCNO="bn/voa/00/voa_0028@0028@voa@bn@en@on">
I 'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Coller</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">VOA News</ENAMEX> .
The crew of destroyer <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USS Cole</ENAMEX> had no reason to expect trouble when the ship pulled into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Aden Harbor</ENAMEX> for a brief routine refueling stop .
As it pulled up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> destroyer , it blew up , tearing a gaping hole in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cole</ENAMEX> 's side .
Admiral <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vern Clark</ENAMEX> , the Chief of Naval Operations , says there had been no threats or warnings ahead of the port call .
Because of general concerns about security in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOC">the Mid East</ENAMEX> , armed guards had been posted on the ship 's deck .
Other standard safety and security measures were also being observed .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Belida</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">VOA News</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pentagon</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
