<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/11/wsj_1170@1170@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Safeway Stores Inc.</ENAMEX> reported a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">69 %</ENAMEX> decline in profit for <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the fiscal third quarter</ENAMEX> , but said operating improvements were masked by unusual gains in the <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">year - earlier</ENAMEX> period .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX> grocery retailer , closely held since a <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 4.2 billion</ENAMEX> leveraged buy - out in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</ENAMEX> , said profit for <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the three months ended Sept. 9</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 7.1 million</ENAMEX> , compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 23 million</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">a year earlier</ENAMEX> .
But it said the <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">year - earlier</ENAMEX> results included gains of <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 23.5 million</ENAMEX> from divestitures .
Sales rose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.2 %</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 3.31 billion</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 3.2 billion</ENAMEX> .
Sales increased <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.5 %</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 9.81 billion</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 9.3 billion</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
