<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/17/wsj_1766@1766@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">International Business Machines Corp.</ENAMEX> will announce on <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</ENAMEX> a slew of software products aimed at eliminating some of the major problems involved in computerizing manufacturing operations , industry executives said .
Many plant floors currently resemble <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">a Tower of Babel</ENAMEX> , with computers , robots and machine tools that generally speak their own language and have trouble talking to each other .
As a result , if a problem develops on a production line , it is unlikely some supervisor sitting in front of a personal computer or workstation will know about it or be able to correct it .
So <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">IBM</ENAMEX> will be announcing <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 50</ENAMEX> products that will be aimed at letting even the dumbest machine tool talk to the smartest mainframe , or anything in between .
In addition , the executives said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">IBM</ENAMEX> will be offering programming tools designed to let anyone working on a factory floor write ad - hoc software , for instance , to do statistical analysis that would pinpoint a problem on a manufacturing line .
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Armonk</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX> , an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">IBM</ENAMEX> spokeswoman confirmed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">IBM</ENAMEX> executives will be announcing some computer - integrated - manufacturing plans <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</ENAMEX> but declined to elaborate .
Also as usual , the products will appeal mostly to heavy users of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">IBM</ENAMEX> equipment , at least initially .
Still , consultants and industry executives said the products could help make manufacturing operations more efficient , and provide a boost to the computer - integrated - manufacturing market -- a market that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Yankee Group</ENAMEX> , a research firm , has said may double to <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 40 billion</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</ENAMEX> .
`` This is a step in the right direction , '' said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Piszczalski</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Yankee Group</ENAMEX> analyst .
He added , though , that `` a lot of this is intentions ... .
We 'll have to wait and see '' how the plan develops .
The announcements also should help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">IBM</ENAMEX> go on the offensive against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Digital Equipment Corp.</ENAMEX> on the plant floor .
While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">IBM</ENAMEX> has traditionally dominated the market for computers on the business side of manufacturing operations and has done well in the market for design tools , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Digital</ENAMEX> has dominated computerized manufacturing .
In addition , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Hewlett - Packard</ENAMEX> , while a much smaller player , has made a big commitment to the sorts of industry standards that facilitate those hookups and could give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">IBM</ENAMEX> some problems .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">IBM</ENAMEX> , which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Gartner Group</ENAMEX> said generates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22 %</ENAMEX> of its revenue in this market , should be able to take advantage of its loyal following among buyers of equipment .
But much will depend on how quickly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">IBM</ENAMEX> can move .
But he said a system such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">IBM</ENAMEX> 's should help significantly .
The computer would let the machine run just until that order was filled , eliminating waste .
This sort of improved link figures to eventually become a significant weapon for some companies .
Salespeople also could get a precise reading on when products could be delivered -- in much the same way that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Federal Express</ENAMEX> has marketed its ability to tell exactly where a package is in the delivery system .
</DOC>
