<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/04/wsj_0499@0499@wsj@nw@en@on">
The ministry said the swap , details of which were disclosed <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</ENAMEX> , will allow both state - controlled companies to reinforce operations in their main markets and argued that the move shows the dynamism of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> 's state - sector concerns .
The approval also ends any hope that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Banque Nationale de Paris</ENAMEX> , another state - sector bank , might have had about taking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Credit Lyonnais 's</ENAMEX> place in the accord .
Under details of the accord , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Credit Lyonnais</ENAMEX> will take slightly more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 %</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Thomson - CSF Finance</ENAMEX> in exchange for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 14 %</ENAMEX> of its own shares .
</DOC>
