<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/18/wsj_1849@1849@wsj@nw@en@on">
Natural upheavals , and most particularly earthquakes , are not only horrible realities in and of themselves , but also symbols through which the state of a society can be construed .
The rubble after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Armenian</ENAMEX> earthquake <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</ENAMEX> disclosed , quite literally , a city whose larger structures had been built with sand .
Did the stock - market tremors of <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday , Oct. 13 ,</ENAMEX> presage larger fragility , far greater upheavals ?
The eerie complacency of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> - Bush era has produced <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Panglossian</ENAMEX> paeans about the present perfection of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economic and social arrangements .
A licensed government intellectual , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Fukuyama</ENAMEX> , recently announced in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">The National Interest</ENAMEX> that history is , so to speak , at an end since the course of human progress has now culminated in the glorious full stop of <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">American</ENAMEX> civilization .
His observations were taken seriously .
But we are , in reality , witnessing the continuing decline of the political economy of capitalism : not so much the end of history but the history of the end .
The financial equivalent of the sand used by those <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Armenian</ENAMEX> contractors is junk bonds and the leveraged buy - outs associated with them .
Builders get away with using sand and financiers junk when society decides it 's okay , necessary even , to look the other way .
By that time they found extremely low profit rates from non-financial corporate investment .
Corresponding to the fall in profit rates was -- in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</ENAMEX> -- the drop in the number arrived at if you divide the market value of firms by the replacement costs of their assets , the famous Q ratio associated with Prof. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Tobin</ENAMEX> .
In theory , the value attached to a firm by the market and the cost of replacing its assets should be the same .
From the history of capitalism we can take it as a sound bet that if it takes <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">only 43 cents</ENAMEX> to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollar</ENAMEX> 's worth of a firm 's capital stock , an alert entrepreneur wo n't look the other way .
Hence the LBO craze .
But here is where the entrepreneur made a very risky bet , and where society was maybe foolish to look the other way .
The mounting risks did not go unobserved , even in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</ENAMEX> .
But there were enough promoters announcing the end of history -LRB- in this case suspension of normal laws of economic gravity -RRB- for society to continue shielding its eyes .
Mainstream economists and commentators , craning their necks up at the great pyramids of junk financing , swiveling their heads to watch the avalanche of leveraged buy - outs , claimed the end result would be a leaner , meaner corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> , with soaring productivity and profits and the weaker gone to the wall .
Left - stream economists I associate with -- fellows in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Union of Radical Political Economists</ENAMEX> , most particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pollin</ENAMEX> of the economics faculty at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the University of California at Riverside</ENAMEX> -- were not hypnotized in the manner of their pliant colleagues .
Corporations need liquidity , in the form of borrowed funds .
the egalitarianism of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> represents the essential achievement of the classless society envisioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> . ''
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fukuyama</ENAMEX> might want to consult some <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">American</ENAMEX> workers on the subject of class and egalitarianism .
From its peak in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</ENAMEX> of $ <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">198.41</ENAMEX> , the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</ENAMEX> wage had fallen to $ <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">169.28</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</ENAMEX> -- both figures being expressed in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</ENAMEX> dollars .
In other words , after the glory boom of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">years</ENAMEX> , wages had sunk from the post <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> peak by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16 %</ENAMEX> as capitalists , helped by the government , turned down the screws or went offshore .
These are long - term Richter readings on <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">American</ENAMEX> capitalism .
The whole structure is extremely shaky .
But sophistication has its limits .
The S-AMP-L bailout could cost <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 300 billion</ENAMEX> , computing interest on the government 's loans .
These are real costs .
Capitalism may now be engineered to withstand sudden shocks , but there are fault lines -- the crisis in profits , the assault on wages , the structural inequity of the system -- that make fools of those who claim that the future is here and that history is over .
</DOC>
