<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/17/wsj_1732@1732@wsj@nw@en@on">
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">hotels</ENAMEX> and management interests will be sold at an auction , said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Rothman</ENAMEX> , president and chief executive officer of the trust and a director of the corporation .
Value of the properties and management interests was n't disclosed .
In all , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> - based trust plans to sell its interests in <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">hotels</ENAMEX> , while the corporation will sell its management interests in <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</ENAMEX> of those properties .
After completing the sale and paying debts , the trust and corporation will consider a number of options including a stock repurchase , payment of special dividend or investment in more gaming properties .
</DOC>
