<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/15/wsj_1534@1534@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Lep Group PLC</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> , which holds a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62.42 %</ENAMEX> stake in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Profit Systems Inc.</ENAMEX> , said it is considering courses of action that could result in its having `` active control '' of the company .
In a filing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Securities and Exchange Commission</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Lep Group</ENAMEX> said a possible course of action may include acquiring some or all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Profit Systems</ENAMEX> shares it does n't already own .
</DOC>
