<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/20/wsj_2078@2078@wsj@nw@en@on">
An experimental vaccine can alter the immune response of people infected with the AIDS virus , a prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> scientist said .
However , that does n't mean they can benefit from the vaccine .
Its effectiveness ca n't be determined until a large clinical trial is undertaken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Army</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">January</ENAMEX> , according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Redfield</ENAMEX> , chief of acquired immune deficiency syndrome research at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Walter Reed Army Institute of Research</ENAMEX> .
Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redfield</ENAMEX> 's report on early experiments using an AIDS vaccine made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">MicroGeneSys Inc.</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Haven</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX> , came at a meeting of AIDS vaccine researchers in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">late Monday</ENAMEX> .
The vaccine , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">VaxSyn HIV - 1</ENAMEX> , has been safely given to <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</ENAMEX> people , some of whom are experiencing substantial increases in certain antibodies .
`` The conventional wisdom used to be that you could n't modify the immune response of an infected individual '' by innoculating them with synthetic viral proteins , Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redfield</ENAMEX> said .
`` We 've demonstrated that you can . ''
He said certain volunteers developed kinds of antibodies associated with early AIDS .
Other antibodies sparked by the preparation are of a sort rarely present in large quantities in infected or ill individuals , he added .
</DOC>
