<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/18/wsj_1822@1822@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</ENAMEX> rules in pending congressional legislation threaten to hinder leveraged buy - outs by raising the price tags of such deals by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as much as 10 %</ENAMEX> .
Wall Street is seething over the rules , which would curtail the tax deductibility of debt used in most LBOs .
The provisions , in deficit - reduction bills recently passed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Senate</ENAMEX> , could further cool the takeover boom that has been the driving force behind the bull market in stocks for much of <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</ENAMEX> , some tax experts and investment bankers argue .
Indeed , some investment bankers have already started restructuring deals to cope with the expected rules .
Wall Street has all but conceded on the issue and is now lobbying for the less onerous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Senate</ENAMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</ENAMEX> of the provisions .
At issue is the deductibility of certain junk bonds that are used in most LBOs .
Such high - yield debt is similar to a zero - coupon bond in that it is sold at a discount to face value , with interest accruing instead of being paid to the holder .
Under current rules , that accrued interest is deductible by the company issuing the debt .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">House</ENAMEX> version of the legislation would kill that deduction , and label any such debt as equity , which is n't deductible .
`` You see these in just about every LBO , '' said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Willens</ENAMEX> , senior vice president in charge of tax issues at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Shearson Lehman Hutton Inc.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> .
Typically , Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willens</ENAMEX> estimates , this type of debt makes up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 % to 20 %</ENAMEX> of the financing for LBOs .
These types of bonds have been used in buy - outs of companies such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">RJR Nabisco Inc.</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Storer Communications Inc.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Kroger Co</ENAMEX> .
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</ENAMEX> provision passed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Senate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">House</ENAMEX> would eliminate a rule allowing companies that post losses resulting from LBO debt to receive refunds of taxes paid over <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous three years</ENAMEX> .
For example , if a company posted a loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 100 million</ENAMEX> from buy - out interest payments , the existing rule would allow the concern to be able to receive a refund from the tax it paid from <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</ENAMEX> , when it may have been a profitable public company .
Several Wall Street officials say the proposed legislation already is having an impact .
Moreover , <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</ENAMEX> investment banker , who requested anonymity , said his firm did n't raise the ante for a target company <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</ENAMEX> after a stronger bid emerged from a public company that was n't concerned about the financing provision .
That would force the buy - out firm and the target company 's management to reduce their level of ownership .
`` The pigs in the trough may have to give a little bit of the slop back and then the deal can go through , '' said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter C. Canellos</ENAMEX> , tax partner at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Wachtell , Lipton , Rosen -AMP- Katz</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">House</ENAMEX> version of the bill would make debt non-deductible if it pays <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</ENAMEX> percentage points above <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Treasury</ENAMEX> notes , has at least a <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">five - year</ENAMEX> maturity and does n't pay interest for <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">at least one year</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</ENAMEX> .
The bill would then declare that the debt is equity and therefore is n't deductible .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Senate</ENAMEX> bill would only deny the deduction until interest is actually paid .
But those holders are often foreign investors and tax - exempt pension funds that do n't pay taxes on their holdings .
`` There 's no question it will make LBOs more expensive , '' he said .
</DOC>
