<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/11/wsj_1169@1169@wsj@nw@en@on">
The company did n't disclose a purchase price or capitalization figures .
The company , which has a <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">European</ENAMEX> foothold , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Murata Europe Management G.m.b . H.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> , said the latest venture is designed to meet demand for electric parts in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">European Community</ENAMEX> countries ahead of the creation of the unified market by <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 1992</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Murata</ENAMEX> expects sales at the unit of <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 1.5 billion yen</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
