<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/06/wsj_0635@0635@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Ciba Corning</ENAMEX> , which had been a 50 - <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</ENAMEX> venture between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Basel</ENAMEX> - based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Ciba - Geigy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Corning</ENAMEX> , has <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</ENAMEX> sales of <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $ 300 million</ENAMEX> , the announcement said .
The announcement said the acquisition should be completed by <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">December</ENAMEX> after a definitive agreement is completed and regulatory approval is received .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Ciba - Geigy</ENAMEX> intends to develop the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Ciba Corning</ENAMEX> unit into a `` substantial business , '' making the unit an `` integral part '' of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Ciba - Geigy 's</ENAMEX> `` comprehensive disease management concept .
</DOC>
