<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/07/wsj_0741@0741@wsj@nw@en@on">
At a time when foreign banks are pouring vast resources and personnel into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Germany 's</ENAMEX> financial center , the opening of a <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</ENAMEX> - man office on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frankfurt</ENAMEX> side street should n't attract much attention .
After an <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">88 - year</ENAMEX> absence from the birthplace of the family banking empire , the return of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschild</ENAMEX> group to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frankfurt</ENAMEX> was greeted by the glare of television lights , curious reporters and a mayoral reception in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Town Hall</ENAMEX> .
Yet the chief reason for the closure , he says , was rooted in a family tradition that would n't allow a bank to bear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschild</ENAMEX> name without a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschild</ENAMEX> in its management .
Much of the family 's mystique remained .
Although its palatial residence was destroyed by bombs during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschilds</ENAMEX> ' place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frankfurt</ENAMEX> 's history is still recalled by the city park and a street bearing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschild</ENAMEX> name .
The family 's long absence is understandable .
The family was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Allied</ENAMEX> countries during both <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War I</ENAMEX> and the long period of economic strife of <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</ENAMEX> .
During <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Third Reich</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschilds</ENAMEX> were a target of <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Nazi</ENAMEX> propaganda against <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Jewish</ENAMEX> financiers .
The persecution pursued the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschilds</ENAMEX> across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOC">Europe</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Nazis</ENAMEX> grabbed countries , confiscating the family 's property in the process .
In <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the immediate postwar years</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschilds</ENAMEX> concentrated on rebuilding their other <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">European</ENAMEX> operations , delaying their return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frankfurt</ENAMEX> .
Indeed , the competition is n't greatly concerned .
`` It would be surprising if they did n't come to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frankfurt</ENAMEX> in time for <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</ENAMEX> , and they bring an interesting tradition .
Instead , it is to seek out corporate financing business and sell investment products on behalf of the family 's mainstay banking units : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">N M Rothschild -AMP- Sons Ltd.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Rothschild -AMP- Cie.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Rothschild Bank AG</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zurich</ENAMEX> .
He left his job as general manager of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Shearson Lehman Hutton Holdings Inc. 's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frankfurt</ENAMEX> office because , he says , `` When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschilds</ENAMEX> called , I could n't resist . ''
In <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">March</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">N M Rothschild</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Rothschild Bank</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zurich</ENAMEX> showed assets of <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY"># 4.1 billion</ENAMEX> -LRB- <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 6.51 billion</ENAMEX> -RRB- and <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">1.26 billion Swiss francs</ENAMEX> -LRB- <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 774 million</ENAMEX> -RRB- , respectively .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> bank does n't publish that figure .
Yet the group 's limited resources makes it a niche player .
`` Obviously , there are quantitative limitations on the assistance we can provide , '' concedes Baron <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David de Rothschild</ENAMEX> , `` but we feel we have some cards to play . ''
As at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zurich</ENAMEX> bank , the minimum investment for individuals will be high : <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">about a million German marks</ENAMEX> -LRB- $ <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">538,000</ENAMEX> -RRB- , <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</ENAMEX> times what many other <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">West German</ENAMEX> investment banks require .
</DOC>
