<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/20/wsj_2097@2097@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Hachette S.A.</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">European</ENAMEX> media and publishing group , reported a small rise in its attributable <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">first - half</ENAMEX> group profit , excluding exceptional items , to <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">133.8 million francs</ENAMEX> -LRB- <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 21.1 million</ENAMEX> -RRB- from <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">130.1 million francs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">a year earlier</ENAMEX> .
Analysts said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Hachette</ENAMEX> 's earnings in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half</ENAMEX> might be boosted by a capital gain from the sale of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> headquarters of a newspaper - delivery company that is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49 %</ENAMEX> owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Hachette</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
