<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/09/wsj_0989@0989@wsj@nw@en@on">
So much of the stuff poured into its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> , offices that its mail rooms there simply stopped delivering it .
Now , <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</ENAMEX> of mailers , catalogs and sales pitches go straight into the trash .
While no one has tracked how many company mail rooms throw out junk mail , direct - mail advertising firms say the number is growing .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">General Motors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</ENAMEX> said it would n't deliver bulk mail or free magazines in its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flint</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX> , office , while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Air Products -AMP- Chemicals</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Allentown</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX> , says it screens junk mail and often throws out most of a given mass mailing .
Why the revolt ?
Though direct mail to businesses is n't broken out separately , the association says it 's growing even faster .
It 's almost impossible to track the number of companies trashing junk mail , since the decision is usually made in the mail room -- not the board room .
And the practice often varies from location to location even within a company .
But industry executives say businesses seem especially inclined to dump mailers sent to titles rather than to individual names .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Motorola</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin</ENAMEX> operation was one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</ENAMEX> to lose patience , deciding <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</ENAMEX> to junk any bulk mail that was n't addressed to an individual .
Magazines are n't delivered at all , even if an individual 's name is listed ; employees who want their magazines have to pick them up from the mail room or the company library -- and are told to change the subscriptions to their home addresses .
At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Air Products</ENAMEX> , meanwhile , the mailroom staff opens junk mail and often throws it away -- even if addressed to an individual .
Direct marketers were especially alarmed when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">General Motors</ENAMEX> -- one of the country 's largest companies and a big direct - mail user itself -- entered the junk - mail battle .
Employees were told that if they really wanted the publications , they would have to have them sent home instead .
`` Why anyone would want to close themselves off -LCB- from direct mail -RCB- , a priori , does n't make any sense , '' says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Bronner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Bronner Slosberg Associates</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> directmail firm .
`` It smacks of big brotherism .
They 're going to decide what their employees can or can not read . ''
The practice is , however , legal in most cases .
So far , they say , it has n't had any noticeable effect on response rates .
And before it does , they 're trying to cut back on the clutter that created the situation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</ENAMEX> place .
`` We 're going to have to mail a lot less and a lot smarter , '' says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Miller</ENAMEX> , president of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Quill Corp.</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lincolnshire</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX> , business - to - business mail - order company .
But then again , mailing less and smarter wo n't be much help if the mail ends up in the garbage anyway .
New <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Hyundai</ENAMEX> Campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Hyundai Motor America</ENAMEX> , fighting quality complaints , declining sales and management turmoil , <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</ENAMEX> unveiled its <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</ENAMEX> ad strategy , tagged `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We 're Making More Sense Than Ever</ENAMEX> . ''
The ad campaign , created by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Saatchi -AMP- Saatchi 's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Backer Spielvogel Bates</ENAMEX> agency , is an extension of the auto company 's `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cars That Make Sense</ENAMEX> '' campaign , which emphasized affordability .
As the announcer reads favorable quotes about the model from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Motor Trend and Road -AMP- Track</ENAMEX> magazines , the other car , which is white , slowly turns green .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</ENAMEX> - page <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Crown Royal</ENAMEX> ad features a black - and - white shot of a boring holiday party -- and a set of colorful stickers with which readers can dress it up .
Both ads were designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Omnicom</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">DDB Needham</ENAMEX> agency .
</DOC>
