<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/15/wsj_1518@1518@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry L. Haines</ENAMEX> , formerly general manager of <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Canadian</ENAMEX> operations , was elected to the new position of vice president , <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">North American</ENAMEX> sales , of this plastics concern .
He remains an executive vice president , the company said , and his new position reflects `` the growing importance of the world automotive market as a market for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">A. Schulman 's</ENAMEX> high performance plastic materials . ''
</DOC>
