<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/07/wsj_0753@0753@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">CRESTMONT FEDERAL SAVINGS -AMP- LOAN ASSOCIATION</ENAMEX> -LRB- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edison</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX> -RRB- --
He will succeed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles L. Harrington</ENAMEX> , chairman and chief executive officer , who retired <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</ENAMEX> .
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seidman</ENAMEX> , a director of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Crestmont</ENAMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">July</ENAMEX> , is general partner of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Seidman Financial Associates</ENAMEX> , which owns <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9.89 %</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Crestmont</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
