<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/02/wsj_0215@0215@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Alltel Corp.</ENAMEX> said it will acquire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">the 55 %</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Pond Branch Telephone Company Inc. 's</ENAMEX> cellular franchise that it does n't own already .
Terms were n't disclosed .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Alltel</ENAMEX> holds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45 %</ENAMEX> of the franchise , which has operations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aiken</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S.C.</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augusta</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ga</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
