<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/20/wsj_2082@2082@wsj@nw@en@on">
Rep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamilton</ENAMEX> said the bill will be modified substantially to call for <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</ENAMEX> meetings <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</ENAMEX> between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Fed</ENAMEX> 's open market committee and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Treasury</ENAMEX> Secretary , the chairman of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Council of Economic Advisers</ENAMEX> and the director of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> .
The original bill was strongly opposed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Fed</ENAMEX> and publicly criticized by friends of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Fed</ENAMEX> as an attempt to undermine the central bank 's independence .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Fed</ENAMEX> critics , however , hailed it as a long overdue attempt to bring a measure of openness and democracy to the setting of monetary policy .
The administration officials do n't ordinarily meet with the entire membership of the open market committee .
</DOC>
