<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/20/wsj_2024@2024@wsj@nw@en@on">
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regal</ENAMEX> had been president and chief executive of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">RBS Industries Inc</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert H. Carlson</ENAMEX> , previous president and chief executive of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Universal - Rundle</ENAMEX> , will assume the title of chairman of the unit , a vitreous - china maker .
</DOC>
