<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/19/wsj_1927@1927@wsj@nw@en@on">
Whether or not `` great cases make bad - law '' -- as Justice <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmes</ENAMEX> asserted -- who can doubt that when great confirmation hearings turn on the nominee 's response to these great cases they make bad judicial history ?
While the book amply justifies its subtitle , the title itself is dubious .
What shook <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> was not a battle for justice but for naked power , in which an army of judicial activists rolled over a judge they had demonized .
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bronner</ENAMEX> seems to believe that the hearings could have gone either way .
I doubt that .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Neas</ENAMEX> was the organizing genius , whipping a conglomerate of pressure groups into an irresistible attacking force .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Harvard</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Laurence Tribe</ENAMEX> was the constitutional heavy , laying out legal strategies for the senators and witnesses to follow .
I add <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</ENAMEX> others .
<ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Republican</ENAMEX> Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlen Specter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> engaged the nominee in a verbal contest aimed at showing that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> was willing to stretch the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</ENAMEX> area -LRB- free speech -RRB- while remaining rigid in all the others .
It achieved a good media play , and enabled Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Specter</ENAMEX> and others to vote against Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> out of `` conscience . ''
The charge of being `` outside the mainstream '' of legal thought gravely undercut Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> 's scholarly standing , leaving him bleeding on the platform .
The nomination still might have been salvaged if a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Democratic</ENAMEX> moderates in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOC">South</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOC">Southwest</ENAMEX> had broken party lines .
Demographics converged with `` mainstream '' and demonizing to seal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork 's</ENAMEX> fate .
The upshot ?
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> 's opponents chose the battlefield , held it and kept it .
Yet with the smooth confirmation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Kennedy</ENAMEX> , an `` <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</ENAMEX> percenter '' only slightly less supportive of judicial restraint than Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Democrats</ENAMEX> may have won the battle but lost the war .
The word went forth to every law school that those with federal court ambitions must travel a safe constitutional journey , with no paper trail and no bite to their tongue or pen .
Probing more deeply into the doctrine of `` judicial restraint , '' he would have found a long history going back to the great decisions of Justice <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmes</ENAMEX> .
He would discover it also in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Bickel</ENAMEX> , a subtle constitutional scholar , Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> 's closest friend at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Yale</ENAMEX> , whose influence on the judge goes well beyond Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bronner</ENAMEX> 's reporting .
Still , the long view of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bork</ENAMEX> as constitutional thinker must be a spotty one .
His strength lies in his majoritarian doctrine , which keeps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Court</ENAMEX> clear of transient group pressures and leaves most decisions in a democracy to elected legislatures and executives .
Unfortunately , Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bork</ENAMEX> failed to distinguish between such pressures and the emergence of great issues critical to a society that must be settled judicially if it is to cohere .
The question of segregated schools , in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Board of Education</ENAMEX> , was such an issue .
In our time abortion has become another , best left to a line of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decisions rather than to the chaos of <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</ENAMEX> state legislatures .
A reflective and growing consensus of <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Americans</ENAMEX> clearly wishes to apply the right to privacy in contraceptive matters -LRB- decided in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griswold</ENAMEX> case -RRB- to abortion as well .
</DOC>
