<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/16/wsj_1630@1630@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Chase Manhattan Corp.</ENAMEX> , after trying unsuccessfully to sell its interest in its lower <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> operations building , has exercised its option to purchase the <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</ENAMEX> - story office tower .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Chase</ENAMEX> had purchased an option to buy the building at One New York Plaza for an undisclosed sum from the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sol Atlas</ENAMEX> as part of its original lease in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</ENAMEX> .
The current transaction cost the bank <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $ 140 million</ENAMEX> .
The building houses <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 4,500</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Chase</ENAMEX> workers , most of whom will be moved to downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> after the bank 's new back office center is completed in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</ENAMEX> .
The move is part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Chase</ENAMEX> 's strategy to consolidate its back offices under <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</ENAMEX> roof .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Chase</ENAMEX> Senior Vice President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Scandalios</ENAMEX> said the bank decided to exercise its option after bids fell short of expectations .
As the building 's new owner , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Chase</ENAMEX> will have its work cut out for it .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Chase</ENAMEX> is vacating <ENAMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1.1 million square feet</ENAMEX> of space , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Salomon Brothers Inc.</ENAMEX> , whose headquarters is in the building , also plans to move shortly .
Even with its striking views of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> harbor , the building is considered antiquated by modern office standards .
</DOC>
