<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/11/wsj_1148@1148@wsj@nw@en@on">
Employees have n't yet been notified .
Sources said that meetings to discuss the staff reductions have been scheduled for <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Mobil</ENAMEX> offices in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> .
This would be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</ENAMEX> round of cuts by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Mobil</ENAMEX> , which along with other oil producers and refiners reduced its work force by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 % to 20 %</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</ENAMEX> as part of an industrywide shakeout .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Mobil</ENAMEX> 's latest move could signal the beginning of further reductions by other oil companies in their domestic oil - producing operations .
In <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">third - quarter</ENAMEX> earnings report , the company alluded to a <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 40 million</ENAMEX> provision for restructuring costs involving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> exploration and production operations .
Most oil companies , including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Mobil</ENAMEX> , have been reporting lower <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">third - quarter</ENAMEX> earnings , largely as a result of lower earnings from chemicals as well as refining and marketing businesses .
<ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Mobil</ENAMEX> said domestic exploration and production operations had a <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 16 million</ENAMEX> loss in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the third quarter</ENAMEX> , while comparable foreign operations earned <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 234 million</ENAMEX> .
Industrywide , oil production in this country fell by <ENAMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">500,000 barrels</ENAMEX> a day to <ENAMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7.7 million barrels</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the first eight months of this year</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Mobil</ENAMEX> executive said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 40 million</ENAMEX> charge related to the action indicates `` a substantial '' number of people will be involved .
</DOC>
