<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/17/wsj_1753@1753@wsj@nw@en@on">
A <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Canadian</ENAMEX> government agency conditionally approved proposed exports to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> of natural gas from big , untapped fields in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOC">Mackenzie River delta</ENAMEX> area of the western <ENAMEX TYPE="LOC">Canadian Arctic</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</ENAMEX> companies , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Esso Resources Canada Ltd.</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Shell Canada Ltd.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Gulf Canada Resources Ltd.</ENAMEX> , applied to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Canadian National Energy Board</ENAMEX> to export <ENAMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">9.2 trillion cubic feet</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOC">Mackenzie delta</ENAMEX> natural gas over <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</ENAMEX> starting in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</ENAMEX> .
To be economically feasible , the <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">11 billion Canadian dollar</ENAMEX> -LRB- <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">US$ 9.37 billion</ENAMEX> -RRB- project requires almost a doubling of natural gas export prices .
The board said the export licenses would be issued on the condition that <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Canadian</ENAMEX> interests would also be allowed to bid for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOC">Mackenzie delta</ENAMEX> gas on terms similar to those offered to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> customers .
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> buyers have already been lined up .
They include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Enron Corp.</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Texas Eastern Corp.</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Pacific Interstate Transmission Co.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Tennessee Gas Pipeline Co</ENAMEX> .
It would bring <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</ENAMEX> gas fields into production at a combined rate of <ENAMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 1.2 billion cubic feet</ENAMEX> a day .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Shell</ENAMEX> , a subsidiary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Royal Dutch / Shell Group</ENAMEX> , will be allowed to export <ENAMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">0.9 trillion cubic feet</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Gulf</ENAMEX> , a unit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Olympia -AMP- York Developments Ltd.</ENAMEX> will be allowed to export <ENAMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3.2 trillion cubic feet</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
