<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/17/wsj_1764@1764@wsj@nw@en@on">
They are : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James R. Eiszner</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">62 years old</ENAMEX> and chairman and chief executive officer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">CPC International Inc.</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert G. Schwartz</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">61</ENAMEX> , chairman , president and chief executive officer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Metropolitan Life Insurance Co.</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter V. Shipley</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">53</ENAMEX> , chairman and chief executive officer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Chemical Banking Corp</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
