<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/04/wsj_0455@0455@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">The Supreme Court</ENAMEX> let stand a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> court 's ruling that the manufacturers of a drug once used to prevent miscarriages must share liability for injuries or deaths when the maker of an individual dose is unknown .
The lawsuits stemmed from the development of cancer and other problems in the daughters of women who took the drug .
On a broader scale , the ruling could encourage other states ' courts to adopt the logic of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> court , not only in DES cases but in other product - related lawsuits , as well .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">New York Court of Appeals</ENAMEX> ruling parallels a <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</ENAMEX> decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the California Supreme Court</ENAMEX> requiring shared liability among manufacturers for injuries when it ca n't be determined which company is at fault .
Now that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> decision has been left intact , other states may follow suit .
The high court refused to hear appeals by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Rexall Drug Co.</ENAMEX> , which went out of business in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</ENAMEX> and was taken over by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">RXDC Liquidating Trust</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">E.R. Squibb -AMP- Sons Inc.</ENAMEX> , a unit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Squibb Corp.</ENAMEX> ; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Eli Lilly -AMP- Co</ENAMEX> .
The appeals involved DES , which was approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> for use from <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</ENAMEX> until <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</ENAMEX> to prevent miscarriages during pregnancy .
In many cases , the lawsuit was filed long after the drug was used -- the cancer in the daughters was typically not detected for <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">years</ENAMEX> -- and there is no way to prove which of several companies manufactured the doses consumed by certain women .
Under traditional legal theories , inability to prove which company manufactured a drug that caused an injury or death would lead to the lawsuit being dismissed .
But in its ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">last April</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> court said that all producers of the anti-miscarriage drug should share liability when the manufacturer of a specific dose ca n't be determined .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> court also upheld a state law , passed in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</ENAMEX> , extending for <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</ENAMEX> the statute of limitations on filing DES lawsuits .
-LRB- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Rexall Drug Co.</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Tigue</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">E.R. Squibb -AMP- Sons Inc.</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Hymowitz</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Eli Lilly -AMP- Co.</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Hymowitz</ENAMEX> -RRB-
Government Contractors
In that decision , the high court said a company must prove that the government approved precise specifications for the contract , that those specifications were met and that the government was warned of any dangers in use of the equipment .
But <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">last February</ENAMEX> , a federal appeals court in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> upheld a damage award against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">General Dynamics</ENAMEX> , rejecting the company 's use of the government contractor defense .
The accident was caused by faulty operation of a valve .
A federal district court awarded damages to the families and the appeals court affirmed the award .
-LRB- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">General Dynamics Corp.</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trevino</ENAMEX>
Court in Brief
In other action <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</ENAMEX> , the high court :
-- Let stand the mail fraud and conspiracy conviction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lavery</ENAMEX> , a former vice president of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Beech - Nut Nutrition Corp.</ENAMEX> , a unit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Nestle S.A</ENAMEX> .
The award was made by a federal court to the widow of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">U.S. Forest Service</ENAMEX> employee who contracted Hodgkin 's disease after using herbicides containing Agent Orange in a weed - killing program .
</DOC>
