<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/02/wsj_0250@0250@wsj@nw@en@on">
Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Democrats</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> administration agreed on a compromise minimum - wage bill , opening the way for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</ENAMEX> wage - floor boost in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">more than nine years</ENAMEX> .
The agreement ended a long impasse between the congressional leaders and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the White House</ENAMEX> over the wage issue .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">White House</ENAMEX> officials were delighted that the compromise includes the concept of a training wage , which Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has fought for throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">White House</ENAMEX> aides said that although they made a small compromise on the length of a training wage , the final minimum - wage increase will meet the standards set by Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> .
The bill vetoed by the president in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">June</ENAMEX> , which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">House</ENAMEX> failed to override , would have lifted the minimum wage to $ <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.55</ENAMEX> an hour by late <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</ENAMEX> , with a training wage for <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">up to two months</ENAMEX> , generally for a worker 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</ENAMEX> job .
Under the compromise , the $ <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.25</ENAMEX> level would be reached <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">nine months earlier</ENAMEX> , while the training subminimum would be shorter , unless it is tied to a training plan .
With congressional elections <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">GOP</ENAMEX> leaders have worried about opposing a minimum - wage rise for low - paid workers at a time when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Congress</ENAMEX> is moving toward a capital - gains tax cut that would directly benefit wealthier taxpayers .
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Senate</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Kennedy</ENAMEX> -LRB- <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">D.</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX> -RRB- , chairman of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Labor Committee</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Domenici</ENAMEX> , -LRB- <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">R.</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.M</ENAMEX> . -RRB- ranking minority member of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Budget Committee</ENAMEX> , have been working on a compromise , and their soundings showed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Senate</ENAMEX> appeared to be heading toward enough strength to override another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> veto , a <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Democratic</ENAMEX> staff official said .
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Democrats</ENAMEX> thought they might have compromised too much .
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> suggested <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Democrats</ENAMEX> `` yielded a great deal '' on the size of the increase , but he cited concessions from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the White House</ENAMEX> on the training wage , which he said make it `` less harsh . ''
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">The AFL - CIO</ENAMEX> , which previously opposed the administration 's subminimum idea , said the compromise has `` adequate safeguards , so the youth are not exploited and older workers are not displaced . ''
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald F. Seib</ENAMEX> contributed to this article .
</DOC>
