<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/06/wsj_0606@0606@wsj@nw@en@on">
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> , president of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Luzon Petrochemical Corp.</ENAMEX> , said the contract was signed <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">USI Far East</ENAMEX> officials .
Contract details , however , have n't been made public .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">USI Far East</ENAMEX> will hold a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 %</ENAMEX> stake in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Luzon Petrochemical</ENAMEX> , according to papers signed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Philippine</ENAMEX> government 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Board of Investments</ENAMEX> .
The proposed petrochemical plant would use naphtha to manufacture the petrochemicals propylene and ethylene and their resin derivatives , polypropylene and polyethylene .
These are the raw materials used in making plastics .
At <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">an estimated $ 360 million</ENAMEX> , the project would represent the single largest foreign investment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> since President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corazon Aquino</ENAMEX> took office in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1986</ENAMEX> .
However , workers ca n't break ground until legal maneuvers to block the complex are resolved , moves which caused the signing to remain questionable <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">up to the last moment</ENAMEX> .
As previously reported , a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">House of Representatives</ENAMEX> has sued to stop the plant .
The legislator , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enrique Garcia</ENAMEX> , had actively backed the plant , but at the original site in his constituency northwest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX> .
The country 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> dismissed the suit , but Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garcia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">late last month</ENAMEX> filed for a reconsideration .
In addition , President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aquino</ENAMEX> has yet to sign into law a bill removing a stiff <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48 %</ENAMEX> tax on naphtha , the principal raw material to be used in the cracker .
`` We have tried our best to tell the people in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bataan</ENAMEX> that maybe this time it will not go to them , but certainly we will do our best to encourage other investors to go to their province , '' Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aquino</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX> - based foreign correspondents .
</DOC>
