<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/19/wsj_1902@1902@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Great American Bank</ENAMEX> said its board approved the formation of a holding company enabling the savings bank to pursue nontraditional banking activities under a new federal law .
The proposed holding company 's primary purpose would be to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Great American</ENAMEX> to continue engaging in real estate development activities , it said .
Those activities generated <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 26.1 million</ENAMEX> in operating profit <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</ENAMEX> .
The new real estate unit would have a separate capital structure to comply with the law .
</DOC>
