<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/20/wsj_2049@2049@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Banc One Corp.</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank E. McKinney</ENAMEX> plans to retire as the bank holding company 's president effective <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 12</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Banc One</ENAMEX> said `` it is contemplated '' that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John B. McCoy</ENAMEX> , chairman and chief executive officer , will assume the additional position of president upon Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX> 's retirement .
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years old</ENAMEX> , was chairman and chief executive of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">American Fletcher Corp.</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> , when that bank holding company merged into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Banc One</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1987</ENAMEX> .
The company said Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX> plans to retire because the process of affiliating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">American Fletcher</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Banc One</ENAMEX> `` is considered completed . ''
He will remain on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Banc One</ENAMEX> board .
</DOC>
