<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/20/wsj_2092@2092@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Control Data Corp.</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> , signed a joint development agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">MIPS Computer Systems Inc.</ENAMEX> to incorporate an emerging computing architecture in future machines .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">MIPS</ENAMEX> is a leader in what is known as reduced - instruction set computing , or RISC , a technology combining microprocessors and sophisticated software .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Digital Equipment Corp.</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Tandem Computers Inc.</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">NEC Corp.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Group Bull</ENAMEX> , among others , have similar arrangements with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">MIPs</ENAMEX> , based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sunnyvale</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif</ENAMEX> .
The accord with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">MIPS</ENAMEX> calls for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Control Data</ENAMEX> to share its expertise in data storage , the companies said .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Control Data</ENAMEX> also said it is developing what it called a `` supermainframe '' computer , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">the Cyber 2000</ENAMEX> , intended for scientists , engineers and other users of generalpurpose high - performance computers .
</DOC>
