<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/16/wsj_1679@1679@wsj@nw@en@on">
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark.</ENAMEX> , department - store retailer said proceeds will be used to reduce short - term debt .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Goldman , Sachs -AMP- Co.</ENAMEX> was the underwriter .
</DOC>
