<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/09/wsj_0972@0972@wsj@nw@en@on">
It seems that <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</ENAMEX> a new movie opens featuring a child coping with a mother 's death , or adoption , or aging parents , or pregnancy .
And why not ?
Some of our best and most idiosyncratic film makers -- from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truffaut</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fellini</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX> -- have taken a cue from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX> : When it comes to compelling drama , there 's no place like home .
Yet too many people working in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> today seem to suffer from the delusion that the drama played out in every home will be interesting to people who live somewhere else .
This is not the case .
Some diaries simply are n't worth snooping in .
Yet there will be people who will sob at `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Immediate Family</ENAMEX> , '' a limply constructed and offensive movie about adoption .
Written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Benedek</ENAMEX> , co-author of `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Big Chill</ENAMEX> , '' `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Immediate Family</ENAMEX> '' takes the position that only rich people living in nice houses should have children .
The film makers have couched this offensive idea in pretty packaging .
Everyone is very nice and good - looking -- the adoptive parents -LRB- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Close</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Woods</ENAMEX> -RRB- and the teen - age couple who decide to give up their baby for adoption -LRB- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Stuart Masterson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Dillon</ENAMEX> -RRB- .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> -LRB- Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX> and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woods</ENAMEX> -RRB- , who seem to be pushing <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">40</ENAMEX> , live in a large and tastefully decorated home in suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> .
Having exhausted all modern aids to fertility , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> decide to adopt .
The actors wear pained expressions to indicate their genuine longing for a little one -- or maybe they 're not - so - subtly commenting on the inadequacy of the script , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Kaplan 's</ENAMEX> -LRB- `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Accused</ENAMEX> '' -RRB- dull direction .
The adoption agency insists on introducing the adopting parents to the birth mother , so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> pay for pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX> 's -LRB- Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Masterson</ENAMEX> -RRB- bus ticket from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> .
I ask this not necessarily as a native <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Ohioan</ENAMEX> . -RRB-
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX> , of course , is pretty and smart , though uneducated .
There is some pain , when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX> has the baby and `` did n't know she would feel like this '' and wants to keep the baby .
But in the end , everything turns out for the best , in the film makers ' warped view .
This picture is about a middle - aged son who makes sure that his delayed bond with his father will last by waiting to cement it until just before the old man dies .
So it 's entirely possible that `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Look Who 's Talking</ENAMEX> '' is n't as entertaining as it seems in comparison to the turgid other films opening now .
It starts with conception , taking the sperm 's point of view , then progresses to the baby 's point of view .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Willis 's</ENAMEX> best attribute as an actor is his coy , lazy voice , and that 's all you get of him here , speaking for the baby .
Finally , there is <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</ENAMEX> family movie that quite eloquently explores the depth of human emotion -- only its stars are bears .
To be sure , one wonders what kind of man is this , who feels compelled to try to understand the most primitive longing and instinct in a way that requires the most sophisticated appreciation of visual storytelling .
`` An orphan bear cub .
A big solitary bear .
<ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</ENAMEX> hunters in the forest .
The animals ' point of view . ''
</DOC>
