<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/05/wsj_0519@0519@wsj@nw@en@on">
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Belgian</ENAMEX> consumer price index rose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">a provisional 0.1 %</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">October</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous month</ENAMEX> and was up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.64 %</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1988</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Ministry of Economic Affairs</ENAMEX> said .
The index , which uses a base of <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</ENAMEX> , was calculated at <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">140.91</ENAMEX> points in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">October</ENAMEX> , from <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">140.74</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">September</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
