<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/20/wsj_2075@2075@wsj@nw@en@on">
But he put off a firm decision while his aides and legislators searched for a compromise that would tighten requirements for such abortions in a way acceptable to the president .
But there still may be prolonged debate and political maneuvering that holds up the <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 156.7 billion</ENAMEX> funding bill for <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the fiscal year that began Oct. 1</ENAMEX> .
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has said he personally approves of abortions in the cases of rape , incest and danger to the life of the mother .
But he has opposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Medicaid</ENAMEX> funding of abortions for poor women who say they are victims of rape and incest , arguing that those exceptions are enforced so loosely that they open the way for abortions for other women .
</DOC>
