<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/05/wsj_0553@0553@wsj@nw@en@on">
But in the end his resignation as Chancellor of the Exchequer may be a good thing , especially if it works as he no doubt intends -- by forcing Prime Minister <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX> and her counterparts elsewhere to confront the genuine intellectual issues involved .
There are the strict monetarists , who believe that floating exchange rates free an economy to stabilize its price level by stabilizing the monetary aggregates .
And there are the twin - deficit Keynesians , who predict / advocate devaluations to balance trade flows .
This is a problem not only for Prime Minister <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX> but for President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> , as shown in the ongoing bickering over the dollar between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Mulford Treasury</ENAMEX> .
He not only slashed marginal tax rates , initially sparking fresh growth in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> , but he wanted to regulate monetary policy by targeting exchange rates , indeed joining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the European Monetary System</ENAMEX> .
While no doubt agreeing with Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawson</ENAMEX> on everything else , Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX> is a dyed - in - the - wool monetarist , inclined to defend floating rates to the death .
As in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> , it also produced a sudden burst in the demand for sterling , that is a surge in the sterling monetary aggregates , M - Whatever .
At this point , the options were : Crunch money to stop the boost in the aggregates , as Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX> surely advised , and forget the soaring pound .
Or to supply enough money to meet the increased demand and stabilize the exchange rate , as the Chancellor argued , and ensure the permanence of this policy by joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">EMS</ENAMEX> .
Faced with a similar situation , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Volcker</ENAMEX> let the dollar soar , -LRB- though monetary aggregates also grew so rapidly monetarists issued egg - on - the - face warnings of inflation -RRB- .
But this devastated the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> manufacturing sector , laying the seeds of protectionism .
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawson</ENAMEX> , though not allowed to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">EMS</ENAMEX> , chose to `` shadow '' the deutsche mark .
He reaped inflation along with rapid growth , no doubt validating Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX> 's predictions in the Prime Minister 's mind .
We had been soliciting opinions on it long before Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawson</ENAMEX> 's resignation , and offer some of the collection for the benefit of his successor and <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</ENAMEX> - time deputy , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Major</ENAMEX> .
To begin with , we should note that in contrast to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> deficit , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> has been running largish budget surpluses .
In pursuit of this mystery , Keynesian adepts and twin - deficit mavens need not apply .
Unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> never achieved even a momentary reduction in real wages .
Inflation is easier to spark and harder to control .
We should also concede that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">British</ENAMEX> experience the monetarist cause regains some of the credibility it lost in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> experience .
We sympathize with Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX> 's reluctance to tie her currency to one governed by the domestic political imperatives of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Germany</ENAMEX> .
Perhaps the shock would have been less if they 'd fixed to another low - tax , deregulated , supply - side economy .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Reynolds</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Polyconomics</ENAMEX> adds his suspicion that the unrecognized inflationary culprit is the budget surplus .
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reynolds</ENAMEX> also notes that since <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">British</ENAMEX> banks have no reserve requirements , high interest rates are less likely to curb inflation than to cause recession .
We would add that in political terms , Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thatcher</ENAMEX> 's problem was failing to decide between the Chancellor and her adviser .
In the end , neither policy was followed , and instead of learning anything we are left with a mystery .
So Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawson</ENAMEX> had to resign .
In the end his move was sparked by remarks in excerpts from Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX> 's autobiography in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The American Economist</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</ENAMEX> - circulation academic journal .
But it was the underlying situation that became intolerable .
Our advice is this : Immediately return the government surpluses to the economy through incentive - maximizing tax cuts , and find some monetary policy target that balances both supply and demand for money -LRB- which neither aggregates nor interest rates can do -RRB- .
This was the version of supply - side economics that , in the <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1970s</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">early '80s</ENAMEX> , worked in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and world - wide to solve a far more serious stagflation than afflicts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">today</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
