<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/15/wsj_1545@1545@wsj@nw@en@on">
PAPERS :
Management and unions representing <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,400</ENAMEX> employees at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Torstar Corp. 's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Toronto Star</ENAMEX> reached a tentative contract agreement <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</ENAMEX> , averting a strike by most employees of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> 's largest <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</ENAMEX> newspaper .
The pact proposes a <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">2 1/2 - year</ENAMEX> contract with a raise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 %</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 %</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 %</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the final six months</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
