<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/20/wsj_2094@2094@wsj@nw@en@on">
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ely</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">57 years old</ENAMEX> , temporarily increases the board to <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</ENAMEX> members .
However , director <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas O'Rourke</ENAMEX> has said he wo n't seek re-election at the company 's <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</ENAMEX> meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
