<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/18/wsj_1852@1852@wsj@nw@en@on">
In a move to prevent any dislocation in the financial markets from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> earthquake , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Securities and Exchange Commission</ENAMEX> said it temporarily reassigned options listed on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Pacific Stock Exchange</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">American</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> stock exchanges and to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Chicago Board Options Exchange</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">SEC</ENAMEX> Chairman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Breeden</ENAMEX> said the cooperation by the exchanges would enable investors to buy and sell options listed solely on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Pacific exchange</ENAMEX> , guaranteeing the liquidity of the market .
Officials at the <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</ENAMEX> exchanges said well over <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</ENAMEX> traders from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Pacific exchange</ENAMEX> were taking flights from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">late yesterday</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">American</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> exchanges and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">CBOE</ENAMEX> , where they would continue making markets in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Pacific</ENAMEX> - listed options .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">The Big Board</ENAMEX> said carpenters quickly erected a new options floor to accomodate <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</ENAMEX> traders from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Pacific exchange</ENAMEX> .
Trading was light on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Pacific Stock Exchange</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</ENAMEX> , with workers at the exchange 's main floor in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> struggling to execute orders by flashlight as a result of a continuing power outage .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">The Pacific exchange</ENAMEX> has options for <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">129</ENAMEX> underlying stock issues , including highly active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Hilton Hotels Corp.</ENAMEX> , which is listed on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Big Board</ENAMEX> .
Investors were concerned that they might be unable to exercise options that expire <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">SEC</ENAMEX> reassigned trading in the options , however , to allow investors to do more than simply exercise the options .
Workers could dial out , but they could n't receive telephone calls .
`` It 's a very uncertain situation right now , '' said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Navin Vyas</ENAMEX> , administrative assistant of trading floor operations of the exchange , which has <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</ENAMEX> volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10 million</ENAMEX> shares .
Because the exchange 's computer was rerouting orders to the exchange 's trading operations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> , `` business is as usual '' Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vyas</ENAMEX> said .
Also , most of the telecommunications equipment was out .
At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Kidder , Peabody -AMP- Co. 's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX> branch , Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet White</ENAMEX> received calls <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</ENAMEX> from workers in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> who offered to work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX> .
Then she discovered that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Quotron Systems Inc. 's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX> lines were down , because they are normally tied in through a system that goes through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> .
So the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Kidder</ENAMEX> brokers had to call other company offices to get quotes on stocks .
At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Quotron</ENAMEX> , the company 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">National Call - In Center</ENAMEX> , which swung into action for <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the first time last month</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane Hugo</ENAMEX> , assembled a tactical team at <ENAMEX TYPE="TIME">5 a.m.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</ENAMEX> to begin rerouting lines and restore service to brokers and traders .
The company dispatched <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 200</ENAMEX> people in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> area to do the work , though most of the rerouting was done by computer .
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Irvine</ENAMEX> , director of the emergency center , said service was being restored to outlying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> areas .
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Options Clearing</ENAMEX> confirmed that it guarantees the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Pacific exchange</ENAMEX> options .
The firm also will permit its members and the public `` to exercise their put and call options contracts traded on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Pacific exchange</ENAMEX> '' even if the exchange is closed , said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Luthringshausen</ENAMEX> , chairman of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Options Clearing</ENAMEX> .
-LRB- Put options give holders the right , but not the obligation , to sell a financial instrument at a specified price , while call options give holders the right , but not the obligation , to buy a financial instrument at a specified price -RRB- .
</DOC>
