<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/02/wsj_0244@0244@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Norway</ENAMEX> 's unemployment rate for <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">October</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.6 %</ENAMEX> , unchanged from <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">September</ENAMEX> but up from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.6 %</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the same month last year</ENAMEX> .
The figure excludes a record number employed by extraordinary government work programs , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Labor Directorate</ENAMEX> announced <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</ENAMEX> .
Including those in the state programs , there were <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">143,800</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Norwegians</ENAMEX> , or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 6.5 %</ENAMEX> of the work force , without permanent employment in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">October</ENAMEX> , up from <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">September</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">136,800</ENAMEX> .
Those employed in state - funded special programs increased by <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,400</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65,200</ENAMEX> in the same period , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Directorate</ENAMEX> said .
</DOC>
