<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/17/wsj_1726@1726@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX> , a federally chartered and shareholder - owned company , said the lenders include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Prudential Home Mortgage Co.</ENAMEX> , a unit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Prudential Insurance Co. of America</ENAMEX> that operates in every state .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Prudential Insurance</ENAMEX> is based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J</ENAMEX> .
The loans can be for accessory apartments , for cottages built in a relative 's yard , for home - sharing or for sale - lease - back transactions .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX> makes a secondary market in home loans .
It buys loans from lenders , packages some into securities for sale to investors and holds the remainder in a portfolio .
</DOC>
