<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/09/wsj_0976@0976@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey 's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Paper Mill Playhouse</ENAMEX> produced this faithful revival of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> 's most influential musical , written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome Kern</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Hammerstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</ENAMEX> produced on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1927</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday , Oct. 28</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="TIME">8 - 10 p.m. EDT</ENAMEX> , on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">HBO</ENAMEX> -LRB- repeated <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 31</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 5</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">8</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">14</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">16</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">20</ENAMEX> -RRB- : `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Perfect Witness</ENAMEX> . ''
Personally , I 'm irked by its combination of ponderousness and timidity , which adds up to an utter lack of drama .
Fans of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Andrews</ENAMEX> -LRB- `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brideshead Revisited</ENAMEX> '' -RRB- will relish watching him play the title role -LRB- s -RRB- in the <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">19th - century</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Louis Stevenson</ENAMEX> pre-Freudian drama of schizoid horror .
<ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday , Oct. 30</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="TIME">10 - 11 p.m. EST</ENAMEX> , on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">PBS</ENAMEX> : `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Journey Into Sleep</ENAMEX> . ''
I promise you will stay awake through this intriguing documentary about the science of sleep .
Critical opinion is divided about the success of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benton</ENAMEX> 's populist defiance of modernist art .
But no one could disagree that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Burns</ENAMEX> has made a fascinating film about this famous <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">American</ENAMEX> painter .
<ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday , Nov. 2</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="TIME">9 - 10 p.m. EST</ENAMEX> , on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">A-AMP-E</ENAMEX> -LRB- repeated at <ENAMEX TYPE="TIME">1 a.m.</ENAMEX> and on <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 5</ENAMEX> -RRB- : `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Third and Oak : The Pool Hall</ENAMEX> . ''
A <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</ENAMEX> - acter by the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer Prize</ENAMEX> - winning playwright <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marsha Norman</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</ENAMEX> presentation in a new series called `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American Playwrights Theater</ENAMEX> , '' sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">General Motors</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Earl Jones</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Van Peebles</ENAMEX> carry out a bitter intergenerational dialogue between <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</ENAMEX> black men .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Woodruff</ENAMEX> hosts this handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</ENAMEX> - part series about the history , economy , culture and politics of the island home of <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Chinese</ENAMEX> democracy and capitalism .
<ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday , Nov. 3</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="TIME">9 - 11 p.m. EST</ENAMEX> , on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">PBS</ENAMEX> : `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our Town</ENAMEX> . ''
I 've seen a great many moviestar film portraits , and this one is outstanding .
<ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday and Monday , Nov. 5 and 6</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="TIME">9 - 11 p.m. EST</ENAMEX> , on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">NBC</ENAMEX> : `` <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Cross of Fire</ENAMEX> . ''
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">The Ku Klux Klan</ENAMEX> was revived in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</ENAMEX> as a national organization aimed at <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Catholics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Jews</ENAMEX> as well as blacks .
<ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</ENAMEX> reason for its downfall was the murder trial of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.C. Stephenson</ENAMEX> , an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> leader whose reckless career is depicted in this film starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Harris</ENAMEX> -LRB- `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">thirtysomething</ENAMEX> '' -RRB- and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Heard</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday , Nov. 7</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="TIME">8 - 9 p.m. EST</ENAMEX> , on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">PBS</ENAMEX> : `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hurricane</ENAMEX> ! ''
Has the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> earthquake caused you to forget <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hugo</ENAMEX> ?
You 'll remember when you see the stunning footage taken from inside a hurricane 's eye , in this edition of `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NOVA</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
