<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/05/wsj_0501@0501@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Japanese</ENAMEX> companies have long been accused of sacrificing profit to boost sales .
But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Fujitsu Ltd.</ENAMEX> has taken that practice to a new extreme .
Its bid : <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">one yen</ENAMEX> , or <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than a U.S. penny</ENAMEX> .
The bid created such a furor that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Fujitsu</ENAMEX> said it is now offering to withdraw from the project .
`` From a common - sense viewpoint , it was not socially acceptable , '' a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Fujitsu</ENAMEX> spokeswoman said <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hiroshima</ENAMEX> city officials could n't be reached to find out whether they would drop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Fujitsu</ENAMEX> 's bid .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Fujitsu</ENAMEX> said it issued the low bid because it wanted a foot in the door of a potentially lucrative market .
`` We desperately wanted the contract because we want experience in the field , '' the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Fujitsu</ENAMEX> spokeswoman said .
It 's a kind of an investment . ''
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hiroshima</ENAMEX> 's waterworks bureau said the municipal government had budgeted <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 11 million yen</ENAMEX> -LRB- $ <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">77,500</ENAMEX> -RRB- for the project .
`` I was flabbergasted , '' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tatsuhara Yamane</ENAMEX> , head of the bureau , was quoted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Kyodo</ENAMEX> news service as saying .
`` I understand the firm 's enthusiasm in getting the deal , but such a large company would have been better off showing a little more discretion . ''
A waterworks official said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Fujitsu</ENAMEX> will have to design the system so it would be compatible with other makers ' equipment .
But industry officials expressed concern that the initial project might give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Fujitsu</ENAMEX> an edge in winning more lucrative contracts later .
`` In the near future , it will be a big market , not just for waterworks , but for all mapping systems , '' the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Fujitsu</ENAMEX> spokeswoman said .
`` We can expect a <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds - of - billions - of - yen</ENAMEX> market . ''
No foreign companies bid on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hiroshima</ENAMEX> project , according to the bureau .
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Japanese</ENAMEX> practice of deep discounting often is cited by <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">Americans</ENAMEX> as a classic barrier to entry in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> 's market .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Fujitsu</ENAMEX> was n't the only company willing to sacrifice profit on the project .
</DOC>
