<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/16/wsj_1649@1649@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Chandler</ENAMEX> , in a <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</ENAMEX> letter defending a weak <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX> book , likened a champion writer to a baseball pitcher .
When the champ has lost his stuff , the great mystery novelist wrote , `` when he can no longer throw the high hard one , he throws his heart instead .
He throws something .
He does n't just walk off the mound and weep . ''
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> might have been predicting the course of his own career .
His last published novel featuring private detective <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Marlowe</ENAMEX> , the inferior `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Playback</ENAMEX> '' -LRB- <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</ENAMEX> -RRB- , at times read almost like a parody of his previous work .
When he died in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> left behind <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</ENAMEX> chapters of yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlowe</ENAMEX> book , `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Poodle Springs Story</ENAMEX> , '' which seemed to go beyond parody into something like burlesque .
Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Parker</ENAMEX> , author of several best sellers featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spenser</ENAMEX> , a contemporary private eye in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlowe</ENAMEX> mold , has with the blessings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> estate been hired to complete `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Poodle Springs Story</ENAMEX> . ''
As the book begins , a newly wed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlowe</ENAMEX> roars into the desert resort of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poodle -LRB- a.k.a . Palm -RRB- Springs</ENAMEX> at the wheel of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Cadillac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fleetwood</ENAMEX> .
That 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> 's setup .
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parker</ENAMEX> spins it into a pretty satisfying tale involving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poodle Springs</ENAMEX> high life , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> low life and various folk who hang their hats in both worlds .
The supporting lineup is solid , the patter is amusing and there 's even a cameo by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernie Ohls</ENAMEX> , the `` good cop '' of previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> books who still does n't hesitate to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlowe</ENAMEX> jailed when it suits his purposes .
All told , Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parker</ENAMEX> does a better job of making a novel out of this abandoned fragment than anyone might have had a right to expect .
Contact lenses , tank tops , prostitutes openly working the streets of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> and the Tequila Sunrise cocktail all seem out of place in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
