<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/14/wsj_1422@1422@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> 's national tobacco company , known for making brown - tobacco cigarettes such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gauloises</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gitanes</ENAMEX> , is branching out .
Concerned by dipping demand for its traditional products , it is moving not only into blonde cigarettes , but also into electronic car - parking payment cards to be sold in neighborhood tobacco stores .
He says that because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Seita</ENAMEX> 's profits are limited by government - controlled cigarette prices , he does n't have the cash to diversify as heavily into food and drink as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> concern has done .
Instead , he said in an interview , he is looking for ways to exploit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> 's network of <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39,000</ENAMEX> tobacco agents , most of them cafes .
One proposal is to introduce a new payment system for parking in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> .
Instead of paying for parking by putting money in the existing machines , which deliver little paper receipts , drivers would be able to buy electronic cards in local tobacco shops .
Once activated , the card would sit in the car 's window , showing traffic wardens how much time the motorist could remain .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Seita</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Matra</ENAMEX> currently are negotiating with city officials for the right to begin service .
And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Seita</ENAMEX> is considering further diversification .
Brown - tobacco cigarettes such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gauloises</ENAMEX> now make up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 40 %</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">French</ENAMEX> tobacco market , <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</ENAMEX> the level of <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">about two decades ago</ENAMEX> .
While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Seita</ENAMEX> retains a manufacturing monopoly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> , it is being hurt by rising imports and from waning cigarette demand .
The aim , says Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Galle</ENAMEX> , is to win market share from imported cigarettes , and to persuade smokers who are switching to blonde cigarettes to keep buying <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">French</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
