<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/09/wsj_0999@0999@wsj@nw@en@on">
HEALTH CLUBS gear up for a graying clientele .
Although their ads picture curvy young people in skimpy outfits , club owners know the future lies with the lumpier <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">over - 40</ENAMEX> set .
`` Most want cardiovascular conditioning ... the No. <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</ENAMEX> way of reducing risk of heart disease . ''
`` Clubs need to be run like restaurants where every square foot makes a <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollar</ENAMEX> , '' he says .
Older people help profits by filling in `` downtime . ''
He adds : `` The medical market and the fitness market parallel each other and are going to cross real soon . ''
People on fixed incomes get a break at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Espre</ENAMEX> ; over <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">55</ENAMEX> wins a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45 %</ENAMEX> discount at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Anaheim Imperial Health Spa</ENAMEX> .
`` HOT '' TOPAZ sparks regulator , jeweler concern over import of irradiated stones .
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> , radiation limits are set and monitored by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">the Nuclear Regulatory Commission</ENAMEX> , which licenses reactors that process the topaz .
`` We believe that the vast majority of imported material is safe .
But there is a small risk that some were imported with high radiation levels . ''
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hickey</ENAMEX> added that the stones found in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> are thought to carry double the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> radiation limit , although he noted that double or even triple the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> limit is `` still in the range of safe levels . ''
<ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">European</ENAMEX> venture capital funds total <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $ 14 billion</ENAMEX> and are expected to continue growing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 %</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> are most often mentioned as the future economic hot spots .
Favored ventures include media , telecommunications and retailing .
Most popular acquisition method : the leveraged buy - out .
Family - owned firms that need cash to grow are attractive , says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Turner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Matuschka Gruppe</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">`` Learning AIDS ''</ENAMEX> lists films , pamphlets , brochures , videos and other educational data .
The distributor is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">R.R. Bowker</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> .
The bureau found that <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> furniture stores could prove their presale prices were higher .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DRACULA</ENAMEX> 'S BUSY <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">this time of year</ENAMEX> , but a visit to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Transylvania</ENAMEX> castle is part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> - based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Unitours</ENAMEX> trip in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</ENAMEX> , presumably the count 's off - season .
But it may have a good listener in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">FCC</ENAMEX> plans to hear a <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">day</ENAMEX> of testimony <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 16</ENAMEX> on the plight of AM radio .
The commission believes that improving AM service would broaden listening selections and increase options for advertisers .
The FM radio band , considered technically superior because it can carry stereo broadcasts , has cornered the airwaves for delivering music .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">The National Association of Broadcasters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">June</ENAMEX> adopted an agenda for revitalizing AM radio that includes , among other things , pursuing further <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">FCC</ENAMEX> action on selecting an AM stereo standard and seeking a law requiring all stereo receivers to include AM stereo .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Lee Co.</ENAMEX> , the jeans maker , celebrates its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">100th</ENAMEX> anniversary with a hardcover yearbook featuring photos of its <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</ENAMEX> employees .
</DOC>
