<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/13/wsj_1357@1357@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">The California Student Aid Commission</ENAMEX> took the action <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 15</ENAMEX> after a government audit cited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">National Technical Schools</ENAMEX> for having courses too short to be eligible for the educational loan program and having a student drop - out rate far in excess of federal standards , and it alleged other serious violations of law and regulations .
The court set a hearing on the emergency action for <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 30</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">United Education -AMP- Software</ENAMEX> posted a $ <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">250,000</ENAMEX> bond against potential losses to the student aid commission and to taxpayers in guaranteeing any more loans for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">National Technical Schools</ENAMEX> students prior to the hearing .
</DOC>
