<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/04/wsj_0408@0408@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Warner</ENAMEX> and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Azoff</ENAMEX> declined comment , as did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">MCA</ENAMEX> , where Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Azoff</ENAMEX> had also been discussing such a venture .
But record industry executives familiar with the talks said Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Azoff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Warner</ENAMEX> came to an agreement <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</ENAMEX> to form a <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50 - 50</ENAMEX> joint - venture company funded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Warner</ENAMEX> and run by Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Azoff</ENAMEX> .
Among other things , they said , Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Azoff</ENAMEX> would develop musical acts for a new record label .
The agreement is said to be similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Warner</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50 - 50</ENAMEX> partnership with record and movie producer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Geffen</ENAMEX> , whose films and records are distributed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX> studio and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Warner</ENAMEX> records unit .
Like Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geffen</ENAMEX> 's arrangement , the venture gives Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Azoff</ENAMEX> a link to the world 's largest and most successful record distributor ; in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> alone , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Warner</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 %</ENAMEX> share of the market , about double its nearest competitor , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Sony Corp. 's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">CBS Records</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">41 - year - old</ENAMEX> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Azoff</ENAMEX> , a former rock 'n' roll manager , is credited with turning around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">MCA</ENAMEX> 's once - moribund music division in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">his six years</ENAMEX> at the company .
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Azoff</ENAMEX> also was eager to return to a more entrepreneurial role in which he had a big financial stake in his own efforts .
</DOC>
