<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/06/wsj_0657@0657@wsj@nw@en@on">
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Nikon Corp.</ENAMEX> said unconsolidated pretax profit increased <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 %</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">12.12 billion yen</ENAMEX> -LRB- <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 85.3 million</ENAMEX> -RRB- in <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half ended Sept. 30</ENAMEX> , from <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.12 billion yen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</ENAMEX> .
Increasing personal spending and capital investment are fueling growth , the company said .
Rising export sales also contributed to strong growth , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Nikon</ENAMEX> added .
Total sales gained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 %</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">122.36 billion yen</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">102.01 billion yen</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Nikon</ENAMEX> forecast sales for <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">the year ending March 31</ENAMEX> will rise <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9.6 %</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">240 billion yen</ENAMEX> .
Pretax profit is expected to increase <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18 %</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">22 billion yen</ENAMEX> and net income is expected to rise <ENAMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53 %</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="MONEY">10.5 billion yen</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
