<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/14/wsj_1476@1476@wsj@nw@en@on">
The official , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John DeVillars</ENAMEX> , asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Clean Harbors</ENAMEX> for more information before ruling on a permit for the site .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Clean Harbors</ENAMEX> , based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quincy</ENAMEX> , said it `` will proceed expeditiously '' to submit the data requested .
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan McKim</ENAMEX> , chief executive officer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Clean Harbors</ENAMEX> said he was `` very much encouraged '' by the official 's praise of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Clean Harbors</ENAMEX> for the quality of some of the data in the report .
</DOC>
