<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/17/wsj_1777@1777@wsj@nw@en@on">
Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Butler</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">60 - year - old</ENAMEX> chairman of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Agricola</ENAMEX> -LRB- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K</ENAMEX> . -RRB- Ltd. , was named chairman of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">County NatWest Investment Management Ltd.</ENAMEX> , the investment management subsidiary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">County NatWest Ltd.</ENAMEX> , the investment banking arm of this <ENAMEX TYPE="NORP">British</ENAMEX> bank .
</DOC>
