<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/08/wsj_0819@0819@wsj@nw@en@on">
One is a strong , vigorous portrayal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> 's play ; the other is director <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory Boyd</ENAMEX> 's overlay of <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">present - day</ENAMEX> punk rock decadence on old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX> .
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelo</ENAMEX> hears that the young man <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claudio</ENAMEX> has made his fiancee pregnant before he could marry her , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelo</ENAMEX> summarily condemns <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claudio</ENAMEX> to death .
When , however , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claudio</ENAMEX> 's sister , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabella</ENAMEX> , a novitiate in a convent , goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelo</ENAMEX> to plead her brother 's case , the obdurate ruler immediately falls in love with her and , in a supreme act of hypocrisy , demands that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabella</ENAMEX> yield up her virtue to him in exchange for her brother 's life .
Meanwhile , the Duke , who set the original scheme in motion , appears on the scene disguised as a friar and becomes involved in a series of intrigues that has everyone fearing the worst possible outcome until the Duke arranges a <ENAMEX TYPE="TIME">last minute</ENAMEX> reprieve for all concerned .
For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Alley</ENAMEX> production , scene designer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter David Gould</ENAMEX> has arranged a stark but extremely effective set featuring a rectangular platform of white - washed boards that extends into the audience .
When the action requires , a prison cell , consisting of an enlarged wire cage , rolls forward on iron wheels on the platform .
In the play 's major scenes Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boyd</ENAMEX> demonstrates that he has a firm grasp of the Shakespearean dynamic .
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabella</ENAMEX> -LRB- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Lauren</ENAMEX> -RRB- confronts her brother <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claudio</ENAMEX> -LRB- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Loney</ENAMEX> -RRB- in his cell , explaining the price she has been asked to secure his freedom ; when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabella</ENAMEX> and the disguised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duke</ENAMEX> -LRB- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Kerr</ENAMEX> -RRB- conspire to trick <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelo</ENAMEX> ; and when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mariana</ENAMEX> -LRB- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annalee Jefferies</ENAMEX> -RRB- , a woman wronged by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelo</ENAMEX> , confronts him with his past misdeeds , the performers bring the dramatic high points to life with intense energy and intelligence .
At such <ENAMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</ENAMEX> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boyd</ENAMEX> makes it clear that he has the capacity to be a superior interpreter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> .
In his `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Measure</ENAMEX> , '' Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boyd</ENAMEX> has `` modernized '' the pimps and prostitutes of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX> whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelo</ENAMEX> is supposed to bring under control by converting them into transvestites , punk rockers and heavy metal types , with a strong emphasis on leather , chains and porno - inspired costumes .
Loud rock music accompanies all the scene changes , even those in the convent .
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claudio</ENAMEX> is arrested , he is brought on stage nude except for the manacles on his wrists and ankles .
When the opportunist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucio</ENAMEX> -LRB- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Stehlin</ENAMEX> -RRB- visits the convent to inform <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabella</ENAMEX> of her brother 's fate , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucio</ENAMEX> not only slaps the mother superior on her rear , but brings along a voluptuous companion -LRB- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Powell</ENAMEX> -RRB- , not in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> 's script , to undulate lasciviously .
The problem here is not in the concept but in its lack of discrimination .
He succeeded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Brown</ENAMEX> , who was fired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Alley</ENAMEX> board <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">18 months ago</ENAMEX> .
Now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Alley</ENAMEX> has moved ahead on both artistic and financial fronts .
Admittedly <ENAMEX TYPE="DATE">last season 's</ENAMEX> runaway hit , `` <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Steel Magnolias</ENAMEX> , '' helped a lot , but so did cost cutting and other measures insisted on by the board .
</DOC>
