<DOC DOCNO="nw/wsj/16/wsj_1662@1662@wsj@nw@en@on">
The market during the start - up is estimated at <ENAMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25,000</ENAMEX> subscribers .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Cable -AMP- Wireless PLC</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> won the other license .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Millicom</ENAMEX> said it would build and operate the system in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Comvik International AB</ENAMEX> , part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Kinnevik</ENAMEX> group of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG">Arfeen International</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> .
</DOC>
